

Profile

Experienced Product Manager and UX expert with a strong focus on web/mobile platforms. Proven track record in enhancing organisational objectives and profitability through deep customer obsession and behavior analysis. Known for strong leadership, adaptability, and creative problem-solving skills. Excels at building relationships, multitasking, and prioritising project requirements for business growth.

Employment History

Senior Product Manager, Ounass, Dubai, UAE

JULY 2022 - PRESENT

As a Senior Product Manager at Ounass, I am dedicated to enhancing the Search and Discoverability functions across the Ounass iOS App and Website. Responsibilities:

- Identified inefficiencies in Fredhopper implementation, reducing query consumption by 45% and saving 28K GBP by initiating and leading optimization project, and achieving Empolyee of the Quarter (Q3, 2023).
- Implemented new product documentation standards (PR-FAQ, PRD, etc.) to enhance stakeholder alignment, streamline project information gathering, and align tasks with OKRs, reducing unecessary requests by 40%.
- Leading the full lifecycle of products, from ideation and validation to technical development, launch, and ongoing enhancement.
- Proactively gathering insights from both internal and external sources to inform
 product concepts. This involves analysing market trends, evaluating competitor
 strategies, assessing new technologies, and synthesising customer feedback to
 guide the development process.
- Promoting cross-functional collaboration with engineering, merchandising, marketing, and customer service teams to meet product goals.
- Managing comprehensive product roadmaps, balancing multiple disciplines and integrating functionalities from various products and programs to deliver cohesive user experiences.
- Continuously identifying unmet customer needs, conceptualising features that address these gaps and enhance the overall user experience.
- Defining and monitoring performance metrics, using quantitative analysis for strategic decisions and product optimisation.
- Overseeing the product backlog, prioritizing tasks based on strategic value and communicating release plans to stakeholders.
- Collaborating with UX teams on user testing with mock-ups and prototypes to ensure designs meet user and business needs.
- Utilising A/B and multivariate tests to optimize the user experience and improve key metrics.

Senior Product Manager / Sales Engineer, Insider, Istanbul, Turkey

JANUARY 2019 - JUNE 2022

Insider is the first integrated Growth Management Platform. It helps digital marketers drive growth across the funnel, from Acquisition to Activation, Retention and Revenue.

As the senior product manager for on-site search product, I was responsible for:

• Launched Eureka as a new product, driving \$50K MRR revenue increase within first year, by overseeing end-to-end implementation and rollout.

Details

Istanbul Turkey

+90 552 352 13 06

hooman.moghani@outlook.com

Links

LinkedIn

Skills

Problem Solving

Strategic Thinking

User-Centric Design

Communication Skills

Data Analysis

Cross-Functional Leadership

Agile and Lean Methodologies

Technical Aptitude

Fast Learner

Languages

English

Persian

- Preparing mockup files and work-flow diagrams while working with Frontend Developers, UI/UX Designers, Backend Developers and Software Architects.
- Effectively prioritising product backlog, running sprints, creating tasks on JIRA, sprint updates, and validating customer & stakeholder expectations. Working closely with the Development, Customer Success, Marketing and Sales Team.
- Preparing Competitor Analysis Documents
- JIRA, Confluence, Postman, Figma, Sketch, draw.io, Trello, Google Analytics, and Google Docs are my toolset in my overall work routine.

Product Manager, Digikala.com, Tehran, Iran

FEBRUARY 2018 - DECEMBER 2018

Digikala Group is a leading e-commerce organisation with a firm grip in multiple online industries including consumer goods, fashion & apparel, e-books, content publishing, digital advertising, big data, fin-tech, FMCG and logistics. Responsibilities:

- Successfully developing and delivering new mobile web/apps revamp, including re-design, running UX experiments, planning, and executing. Doubling the daily Mobile Web's orders.
- Managed business objectives (KPIs) and prioritisation of product roadmap.
- Managed strategic product planning and marketing strategies to promote maximum product visibility.
- Effectively prioritise product backlog, validate customer response, and provide fast feedback. Lead the product development initiatives utilising user and competitive research.
- Analysed apps traffic and statistics, using GA, Hot Jar, and Firbase, to improve customer experience, conversions/user interaction.
- Provided strong organisational leadership and technical support putting together sales and business development teams that resulted in significant success in profit revenue.

Product Manager, SnappTrip, Tehran, Iran

MAY 2017 - JANUARY 2018

As part of SnappGroup (Former Rocket Internet Company), SnappTrip is a full service travel booking website and its mission is to empower customer choice in booking their whole travel.

In my role as Product Manager, I spearheaded the strategy, development, and performance optimization of our Hotel and Flight product verticals, consistently delivering value and enhancing the customer journey. Responsibilities:

- Developed a data-driven strategy for Hotel and Flight bookings, enhancing customer value and business growth. Led cross-functional teams to launch innovative solutions, addressing user needs and achieving business goals.
- Utilized customer insights for product design, improving the booking experience and increasing customer satisfaction and loyalty.
- Managed product performance metrics and iterative testing to align with business objectives and foster continuous improvement.
- Engaged with key stakeholders across departments to ensure unified product vision and execution.
- Drove revenue growth for Hotel and Flight products through data-driven optimization of pricing and features, increasing market share.
- Emphasized agile development and iterative testing to quickly adapt to market changes and customer feedback, keeping SnappTrip competitive in the travel industry.

Achievements:

• Launched impactful booking features, enhancing user experience.

- Achieved growth in bookings and revenue for Hotel and Flight lines via strategic enhancements.
- Improved customer engagement and retention through user-centric design and continuous iteration based on feedback.

Product Owner / User Experience Consultant, VADA House of Mobile, Tehran, Iran

JANUARY 2015 - APRIL 2017

VADA is a mobile content provider company. Their field of activity is mobile apps, digital media, and social networks.

As a Product Owner, I was responsible for ensuring the business measures and the performance of several Mobile Applications.

Education

Project Management (Master's Degree), University of Wollongong, Wollongong, Australia

JUNE 2010 - JUNE 2012

Industrial Engineering (Bachelor Degree), Azad University, Tehran, Iran

JUNE 2005 - JUNE 2009

Courses

Google Project Management: Professional Certificate, Coursera

JANUARY 2024 - MARCH 2024

IBM Product Manager Professional Certificate, Coursera

FEBRUARY 2024 - MAY 2024

References

Ujwal Tickoo from Digikala.com

ujwaltickoo@gmail.com | +91 77278 60433

Ajish Pillai from Insider

ajish@useinsider.com | +971 58 585 9047

Nergis Tamer from Ounass

ntamer@altayer.com | +90 506 225 77 02